我们现在正在运行这个容器，我在这里暴露了 3000 端口。
We are now running this container and
I've exposed Port 3,000 here.
所以如果我们在这里运行一个容器，它就会暴露在端口 3000 上，好吗 ?
So if we run a container in here,
it will be exposed on port 3,000, okay?
因此，我们将使用 Buildah 在此处的一个源中构建一个 Buildah 容器。
So then, we're gonna use Buildah to build
a Buildah container inside a source here.
所以，如果你看，这有一个 Docker 文件，是我们的索引点。
So if you look, this has a Docker file,
it's our index dot js.
如果我说猫咪指数点你可以看到
If I say cat index dot js,
you can see here,
我们之前写了几章只是我们的节点服务好吗
it's just our node service that we
wrote a couple of chapters ago, okay?
现在， Buildah 有一种特殊的方法来建造可以进入的容器。
Now Buildah has a particular way of
building containers that you can go in.
这是一种以交互方式构建的构建。
It's kind of built to
be built interactively.
所以不要有 Docker 文件你就会说
So rather than having a Docker file,
you go and you say,
好了我们从这儿开始然后去集装箱
okay, we're gonna start from here and
then do this to the container.
你以交互方式直接执行命令行。
And you do it just with
the command line interactively.
这是一种制造容器的有趣方法。
It's kind of a fun way
to build containers.
我们不会这么做因为要花很多时间
We're not gonna be doing that because
it would take a bunch of time.
如果你有兴趣做 Buildah，我会让你去做的。
And I'll leave you to do that if
you're interested in doing Buildah.
这只是把你介绍给你
This is more just to introduce you to it.
我要做的是我要说的是 buildah
What I'm gonna do instead
is I'm gonna say buildah.
然后，您可以使用 -docker-file 构建。
And then,
you can say build-using -docker-file.
所以 Buildah 知道如何读取 Docker 文件，这很酷，对吧 ?
So Buildah knows how to read Docker files,
which is pretty cool, right?
或者如果您不想输入 build - using -dockerfile，
Or if you don't wanna type
build-using-dockerfile,
它们缩短了到 Bud ， build-using -dockerfile。
they shortened that to bud,
build-using-dockerfile.
您告诉它该文件，即点斜杠 Dockerfile。
You tell it the file,
which is dot slash Dockerfile.
你会给它一个标签就像你和 Docker一样
And you're gonna give it a tag
just like you would with Docker.
你会说我的 app - app -buildah。
And you're gonna say my-app-buildah.
不管你想做什么
Whatever you wanna tag it,
and then period.
所以，从那里，它将会去安装所有你需要的东西。
So from there, it's gonna go and install
all the necessary things that you need.
它会把它们从 Docker 集线器中拿走
It's gonna go grab them off of Docker hub.
我不知道为什么这么闪
I don't know why it's flashing so much.
因此，这将需要第二个 cuz ，这不会从 Docker 高速缓存中提取，对吗 ?
So this will take a second cuz this is not
gonna pull from the Docker cache, right?
它是一个产品，而不是 Docker。
Cuz this is a product than Docker.
所以下载的节点有 12个
So that downloaded node 12-stretch.
你也可以把这个更改为节点 alpine ，会没事的
You could also change this to node alpine,
it'd be totally fine and
下载的时间会少一些
it would take a little
less time to download.
这件作品将会被片段和构建我们的 Docker 文件
And this is gonna go piece by piece and
build our Docker file, or
使用 Docker 文件构建容器。
build a container with our Docker file.
你可以看到，我们的 npm 安装在那里。
So you can see there,
it's running our npm install there.
它会运行 npm 的
It's gonna run npm ci.
复制节点目录。
Copy our node directory over.
然后你就可以了
And there you go.
我们使用 Docker 文件成功构建了 Buildah 容器。
We successfully built a Buildah
container using a Docker file.
我们来做个 buildah 检查吧。
So let's do a buildah inspect.
我叫什么叫我 - app-app -buildah?
What did I call,
did I call it my-app-buildah?
我想我知道了
I think I did.
同一件事
Same thing here.
你可以看到它所做的各种事情。
You can see all the various things it did.
你可以看到它所做的所有层，等等。
You can see all the layers that it did,
so on and so forth.
好吗 ?
Okay?
因此， Buildah 可以做的事情与波德曼可以做的事有一些重叠。
So there is some overlap between what
Buildah can do and what do Podman can do.
不像你想象的那么干净
It's not as clean cut as
you might think it is.
实际上，您也可以使用 Buildah 来运行容器，但是
You can actually use Buildah
to run containers as well, but
您可以更多地使用 Docker 来运行一个命令，然后完成场景的类型。
you use it more to do the Docker run one
command and then finish kind of scenario.
Podman 更希望运行 Web 服务器，并希望您管理
Podman is more for I wanna run a web
server and I want you to manage this for
我，对吧 ?
me, right?
而 Buildah 可以说，嘿，用容器做一件事，然后完成。
Whereas Buildah can say, hey, do a thing
with a container and then finish.
所以他们在 Buildah 和 Podman之间有点不同
So they kinda separate that out
between Buildah and Podman.
所以我们能做的就是
So what we could do here is we can say
buildah 运行破折号网主机，我的应用程序。
buildah run dash dash net host, my app.
我得先做这件事
I have to do that thing first.
你必须这么做抱歉
You have to do this, sorry.
我的 app - app -buildah ，就像这样。
Buildah from my-app-buildah, like that.
您必须首先启动容器。
Cuz you have to get
the container started first.
所以现在我开始了
So now, I have it started.
我能做个建筑吗
Can I do like a buildah ps?
它知道怎么做吗
Does it know how to do that?
确实有 好的
It does.
Okay, so
我可以看到这里是我开始的
I can see here that I've started this.
我有，它是在后台运行的。
And I have,
it's running in the background.
我的 app - app-buildah - 工作容器。
So the my-app-buildah-working-container.
这是图片，我的 app - buildah ，然后工作容器的实际情况
So this is the image, my-app-buildah,
and then working-container's actually
在此时刻执行的容器。
the executing container
at this moment in time.
现在我能做的是我能说
And then now, what I can do is I can say,
buildah 运行破折号网络主机 my-app-buildah。
buildah run dash dash
net host my-app-buildah.
或者我只是把它贴在上面
Or I just paste that in
there from up there.
我的 app - app-buildah - 工作容器，它就是这样叫它的。
my-app-buildah-working-container, which
is what it called it right there.
然后我就能穿过破折号的太空堡垒
And then,
I can pass into it dash dash space bash.
这将会对我的容器执行这一步骤
And this will execute that against the
container which is going to drop me into
执行容器。
the executing container.
那么现在我就在一个容器里面的一个容器里面，对吧 ?
So now, I'm inside of a container
which is inside of a container, right?
所以我就在一个内置了 Buildah 的 Docker 容器里面
So I'm inside of a Docker container which
had Buildah installed, and then I used
用于执行在同一上下文中运行的容器。
that to execute the container which is
running inside of the same context.
所以，现在，如果我说猫的问题，我们希望看到什么 ?
So now, if I say cat/etc/issue,
what do we expect to see?
Debian ，因为这就是我们用它建造的容器。
Debian, because that's what
we built our container with.
现在，你可以看到我在这里，我可以说点节点索引点，
And now, you can see I'm here,
I could say node index dot js, and
一切都会好的
everything will execute just fine.
会很棒的
And it'll be great.
所以别这样了我们就离开这里
So let's stop that,
we'll exit out of here.
我可以说 " buildah " ，它是否停止了 ?
And I can say buildah, is it stop?
[ INAUDIBLE] 我不记得了
[INAUDIBLE] I don't remember.
杀了吧
Kill, maybe?
除去。
Remove.
是的，我可以说， buildah rm 是我的 - app-buildah - 工作容器。
Yep, so I can say buildah rm
my-app-buildah-working-container.
这样就能让集装箱从运行中关闭。
And that'll go and actually shut
down the container from running.
这就是 Buildah 能为你做的
So that's kind of what Buildah can do for
you.
就像我说的波德曼有一些重叠
And like I said,
there's some overlap with Podman,
cuz Podman 用于执行容器。
cuz Podman is built for
executing containers.
Buildah更多的是为了建造容器而建造的。
Buildah's more, as it may sound,
built for building containers.
但在他们能做的事情上也有一些重叠。
But there's some overlap
in what they can do.